gaystarnews.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - Gay Star News

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Data collected, used and stored by Gay Star News Ltd having its registered office at Gay Star News Ltd (GSN), 129 Mile End Road, London, E1 4BG, UK, a company registered in England and Wales. Registered number: 7719609. (Privacy Policy updated on 7 June 2019.)

GSN takes your privacy very seriously. We do everything we can to communicate the information on our website accurately and in an easy to understand way. GSN endeavours to take appropriate technical and organisational measures in processing Personal Data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) (EU) 2016/679.

This Privacy Policy explains the types of Personal Data we collect from and about you and how we use, disclose and protect that data as well as your ability to control certain uses of it.

## Definitions and legal references

### Personal Data (or Data / User Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Website (or third-party services employed in this Website), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Website, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Website) and the details about the path followed within the Website with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

### User

The individual using this Website, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.

### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Website. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Website.

### This Website

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

### Cookies

Small sets of data stored in the User's device.

## Owner and Data Controller

The Owner of this Website is GSN.

If you need to contact GSN in relation to the use of your Personal Data on our website the Data Controllers are listed below with their contact details.

  * David Young / davidy@gaystarnews.com

## What is personal data?

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. This includes, for example; your name, telephone number, address and e-mail address.

## What Personal Data do we collect?

Among the types of Personal Data that this Website collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage Data and email address.

Complete details on each type of Personal Data collected are provided in the dedicated sections of this privacy policy or by specific explanation texts displayed prior to the Data collection.

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or, in case of Usage Data, collected automatically when using this Website.

All Data requested by this Website is mandatory and failure to provide this Data may make it impossible for this Website to provide its services. In cases where this Website specifically states that some Data is not mandatory, Users are free not to communicate this Data without any consequences on the availability or the functioning of the service.

Users who are uncertain about which Personal Data is mandatory are welcome to contact the Data Controller.

Any use of Cookies – or of other tracking tools – by this Website or by the owners of third-party services used by this Website serves the purpose of providing the service required by the User, in addition to any other purposes described in the present document and in the Cookie Policy.

Users are responsible for any third-party Personal Data obtained, published or shared through this Website and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

Protect: In order to check login activity and potentially block fraudulent attempts, the following information is used: attempting user’s IP address, attempting user’s email address/username (i.e. according to the value they were attempting to use during the login process), and all IP-related HTTP headers attached to the attempting user.

## How do we store and process User Data?

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third-party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

### The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Analytics, Displaying content from external platforms, Tag Management and Managing contacts and sending messages.

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

Google Analytics (Google, Inc.)

  * Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Website, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.
  * Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

Alexa (Alexa Internet, Inc. an amazon.com company)

  * Alexa measures Internet activity in order to understand trends, help people discover new content, and help people make better online decisions. Alexa provides Toolbar Service users with information about Internet trends, website popularity, new and exciting topics, and related content.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://www.alexa.com/help/privacy) – [Opt Out](https://support.alexa.com/hc/en-us/articles/200685410-Opting-Out-of-Alexa-Measurement-Pixel)

### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of service allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Website and interact with them.

This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

The Rubicon Project (Rubicon Project, Inc.)

  * Rubicon is a programmatic advertising service.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/)

DoubleClick (Google, Inc.)

  * DoubleClick is a programmatic advertising service.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/) \- [Opt Out](https://adssettings.google.com/)

Instagram (Instagram, Inc.)

  * Instagram is an image visualization service provided by Instagram, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://help.instagram.com/519522125107875?helpref=page_content)

YouTube (Google, Inc.)

  * YouTube is an video content visualization service provided by Google, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy/update?hl=en-GB&gl=uk)

Vimeo (Vimeo, LLC)

  * Vimeo is an video content visualization service provided by Vimeo, LLC that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://vimeo.com/privacy)

Tumblr (Tumblr, Inc.)

  * Tumblr is an owner built content service provided by Tumblr, Inc. that allows this Website to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.tumblr.com/privacy/en_eu)

### Content commenting

This type of service allows you to comment on content and share from this Website on social media.

Facebook (Facebook, Inc.)

  * Facebook Comments is content commenting service provided by Facebook, Inc. enabling the User to leave comment and share them on the Facebook platform.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update)

### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This application allows you to interact with the social widgets of social media platforms liked through this Website.

GetSocial (GetSocial)

  * GetSocial is a content performance analytics platform that helps marketers & publishers measure, promote and amplify their best content.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: Germany – [Privacy Policy](https://getsocial.io/privacy-policy)

Facebook (Facebook, Inc.)

  * The Facebook like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update)

Twitter (Twitter, Inc.)

  * The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter, Inc.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy)

### Gathering results for surveys, polls, votes and competitions

This type of service lets you contribute to research undertaken by this Website for surveys, polls, votes and competitions.

This service will not collect sensitive data about a User without them knowingly or explicitly consenting to provide it.

SurveyMonkey (SurveyMonkey, Inc)

  * SurveyMonkey is an online survey platform.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/?ut_source=footer)

### Online payment processing

This type of service makes it possible for you to process monetary transactions with this Website.

If you are a Customer, when you make payments or conduct transactions through a Stripe User’s website or application, they will receive your transaction information. Stripe may receive this information directly from you, or from the Stripe User or third parties. The information that is collected will include payment method information (such as credit or debit card number, or bank account information), purchase amount, date of purchase, and payment method. Different payment methods may require the collection of different categories of information. The payment method information that will be collected will depend upon the payment method that you choose to use from the list of available payment methods that are offered to you by the Stripe User.

Stripe (Stripe, Inc.)

  * Stripe is a payment processing service.
  * Personal data collected:
  * Both Sites use cookies and other technologies to function effectively. These technologies record information about your use of our Sites, including:
  * Browser and device data, such as IP address, device type, operating system and Internet browser type, screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, plug-ins, add-ons and the language version of the Sites you are visiting;
  * Usage data, such as time spent on the Sites, pages visited, links clicked, language preferences, and the pages that led or referred you to our Sites.
  * For all transactions data collected by both sites is: full legal name, email address, IP address, location (derived from IP address), Operating System, last 4 digits of your card number, and card expiry date.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy)

### Managing contacts and sending messages

We may send you email notifications regarding specific requests made by you or service-related emails. You have the ability to opt out of any of this communication at any time using the link at the bottom of the newsletter email or alternatively please contact the Data Controller.

This type of service makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.

These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

  * MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.
  * Personal Data collected: email address.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.surveymonkey.com/mp/legal/privacy-policy/?ut_source=footer)

### Tag Management

This type of service helps the Owner to manage the tags or scripts needed on this Website in a centralized fashion.

This results in the Users' Data flowing through these services, potentially resulting in the retention of this Data.

Google Tag Manager (Google LLC)

  * Google Tag Manager is a tag management service provided by Google LLC.
  * Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.
  * Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Website or the related services.

The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities.

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Website may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request.

### System logs and maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Website and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Website (System logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address).

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document.

### The rights of Users

You have the right not to be tracked on our Website. To learn more about activating the “Do Not Track” mode, please click [here](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments through social media, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Security

We take many precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

Whilst we go to great length to ensure any confidential information remains protected we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet.

You are responsible for keeping your user details confidential and at any moment we will request any passwords or access codes so please don’t trust them to anybody asking.

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Website and can request that the Data Controller remove the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users.

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by iubenda and hosted on iubenda's servers.
